MILDRED MAKORI FRONT END ENGINEER

+254 711 711 701 • GitHub • LinkedIn • Medium • twitter

PERSONAL PROFILE

A Software Engineer graduate specialized in front end web, very passionate, honest, loves learning and enjoys being challenged. Looking to secure a position to use and further develop my skills in a practical, fast-paced environment. Has used tactical and, team-focused approaches to drive people to project completion. I have 5 yrs experience in UX/UI

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript | CSS/CSS3 | Sass | HTML5 | C | TypeScript | Python

Frameworks/Libraries: Reactjs | npm | NodeJS | jQuery| Tailwind CSS | Python Flask | SQL | WordPress | Bash/git | Bootstrap

Version Control: GitHub

Database Management: MYSQL | MongoDB

Design Tools: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Canva, Invision

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MiRo Technologies -Co-founder & Team Lead March 2018 to present Responsible for leading a team of 4 people tasked with improving

front-end deployments that were not agile and taking up 2 hours, and reduced it to 1 hour.

Troubleshoot website problems & Create and test applications for websites & Responsible for Hiring,

Training our clients on how to use specific software in case they encounter any challenges.

UCESCO Africa -Volunteer November 2022 to Present

- Create and test applications for websites, Troubleshoot website broblems.
- Maintain and update the website & Monitor website traffic. Which In return increased up to 70% funding and page visits.
- Introduced online payment, to curb the key pain points experienced by donors using offline payments which in return increased to almost 20% donations increase!

EldoHub -Web Developer & Designer (Remote) -Contract March 2021 to June 2021.

Built an e-commerce website in WordPress to digitize the process of bnline shopping, Which in return generated a 7% profit margin.

Andela -Front Engineering Intern -Contract March 2021 - June 2021

- Was Responsible for website design and development for the clients.
- Led update sync meetings on the status of the websites during sprints that translated to positive attendance and beating the project deadline.

Deveint -Front-End Engineer Intern -Jan 2017 - April 2017 Create and test applications ensuring edge cases is tested and

bassed.

AkiraChix - Volunteer -April 2016 - May 2016

Assisted over 10 children with projects on Arduino programming, developing and designing websites, and helped them enhance their crafting skills through art projects.

PRE-PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Call Center interviewer at Consumer
- Headgirl at Chemamul High school

EDUCATION

ALX (Holberton)-Software 2021 - 2022 Engineering-

> AkiraChix- Web & Graphic Designer

The Technical University of Kenya(TUK)- Diploma in 2012 - 2015 2016

Aeronautical Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Fundamentals by Microsoft

INTERESTS

Keen Interest in Research and development in tech industry and poverty alleviation

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Career spike- A job board platform to list entry level jobs Housefy- a platform to list houses to rent and buy

REFEREES

Available upon Request